Guide to the Kirsten Flagstad Collection
Kirsten Flagstad collection,
- Gift from Kir and Nancy to Kirsten, Else, Arthur and Sigurd, December 1, 1962Dec. 1, 1962, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 190-18; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6212011)
  Recording: Gift to Kirsten Flagstad on her deathbed. Includes message from Kir and Nancy in pidgin-Norwegian followed by re-recordings from some of Flagstad's discs with English translations of the lyrics. Sinding, Christian, 1856-1941. Galmandssange. Mainat -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Romancer og sange, op. 18. Efteraarsstormen -- Bull, Ole, 1810-1880. Sæterjentens søndag -- Lie, Sigurd, 1871-1904. Sne -- Alnæs, Eyvind, 1872-1932. Sange, op. 26. Lykken mellem to mennesker -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Romancer, op. 15. Modersorg; Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig; Lieder, op. 48. Traum -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Zärtliche Liebe -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Forelle (Song); An die Musik.
- On singing Wagner, June 28, 1956 (side 1); About Flagstad's farewell, December 26, 1953 (side 2).1956, 1953, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Full-range FR-5; 5 in. (Box 7, Folder 5606281)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Hagermann-Lindencrøne, Knud Side 1. Kirsten Flagstad discusses "On singing Wagner" in English with examples from Walküre, Act 2, scene 4, Tristan und Isolde, Act 1, scene 3 (both with Set Svanholm) and Die Forrelle by Schubert. Side 2. Knud Hegermann-Lindencrøne talks in Danish on Danish Radio "About Flagstad's farewell" describing her farewell concert in Oslo, 1953. Includes musical excerpts from An die Musik by Franz Schubert (with piano) and Ein Traum by Edvard Grieg (with orchestra).
- Interview with Kirsten Flagstad on Danish RadioSeptember 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch; 5 in. (Box 7, Folder 5609001)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Hagermann-Lindencrøne, Knud Interview by Knud Hegermann-Lindencrøne with Kirsten Flagstad on Danish Radio, September 1956.
  Danmarks radio; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962--Interviews
- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Carnaval; Gjerstrøm, Gunnar, 1891-1951. Concerto, piano, F minor1959, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 311; 5 in. (Box 7, Folder 6000001)
  Performers: Waldemar Alme, piano
  Piano music; Concertos (Piano)
- Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Grandes études de Paganini. No 3, Campanella; Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Sonata, piano, B minor1950, 1960, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono., Soundcraft; 5 in. (Box 7, Folder 6000002)
  Performers: Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Both works recorded in 1950 and re-recorded to tape ca. 1960.